

Nyi Nyi Zaw

Experience Android Software Engineer

Sukhumvit 87 Alley, Bang Chak, Phra Khanong, Bangkok 10260 🛗 17/12/1996 🏲 Myanamr

💄 He/Him 🛮 in Nyi Nyi Zaw 🎔 @nyinyi2aw 🕥 nyinyiz M Nyi Nyi Zaw

Profile

I am a skilled Android developer with six years of experience building and maintaining a wide range of Android applications. Also I have two years of experience with Flutter in a Singapore company.

In my current role as an Android Engineer at True Digital Group, I have been responsible for designing and implementing new features, as well as maintaining and improving existing functionality. I have also worked closely with the rest of the engineering team to troubleshoot and resolve any issues that may arise.

Skills

Programming languages

Java, Kotlin, Dart, Swift

Frameworks and tools

Android, Flutter, iOS, Git, HMS

Other

Strong problem-solving skills, ability to work in a team environment, ability to learn and adapt to new technologies quickly.

Professional Experience

Android Software Engineer, *True Digital Group* □

- Working as an Android Soware Engineer (Technology Manager) in Architecture and Technology Strategy.
- Main focus on TrueID international products and features.
- Collaborated with a team of developers to ensure timely and successful delivery of the application.
- Conducted unit and integration testing to ensure the application was stable and performed as expected.

Mobile Developer (Remote from Bangkok), GTRIIP ☑

- Integrate and support existing Flutter projects running in production.
- The first integration of an Android native SDK (library) for a company product was a door lock SDK.
- Worked closely with the product team to gather and incorporate user feedback into the development process.
- Conducted performance testing and optimization to ensure the applications ran smoothly on a variety of hardware configurations.

07/2022 – present Bangkok, Thailand

09/2021 - 07/2022

Bangkok, Thailand

Mobile Lead, UMFCCI □ 02/2021 - 09/2021 • Led a team of mobile developers in the development of a cross-platform mobile Yangon, application for a communication platform. Myanmar (Burma) • Integrate the notification service to support both Google and Huawei devices into the notification module. • Deploy the app on both iOS and Android platforms using Flutter while leading the mobile team. • Managed the development process, including setting project timelines, assigning tasks, and conducting code reviews. Senior Android Developer, Codigo ☑ 06/2019 - 02/2021 **ComfortDelgro** 🗷 Yangon, • Used Kotlin for Android to implement features such as user authentication, point Myanmar (Burma) system integration, and payment processing. Integrate new payment options such as NETS Click and PayLah! for Singapore region. • Integrate Huawei Mobile Service as the first HMS Taxi app in Asia to maximize users' experiences while using the app from Huawei devices. • I developed a point system e-commerce platform for a taxi app. • I collaborate and communicated with people in over 3 countries while developing an application. • I was able to increase the user experience rating in the PlayStore from 2.0 to 4.4. • Handle multiple versions of the application in parallel to enable backward and forward compatibility, as well as bug fixes between different application versions, to provide customers with smooth application upgrades and transactions. Senior Mobile Developer, AcePlus ☑ 01/2019 - 06/2019 • Supported as mobile teams lead and design software requirements and Yangon, architecture. Myanmar (Burma) I handled multi-platform products for both native Android and iOS within a tight timeline. • Performance improved and maintained the legacy Java codebase to Kotlin using MVVM. • Given training and guidelines for Modern Android Development (MAD). **Mobile Application Developer,** *Global New Wave Technology* □ 09/2017 - 01/2019 • I developed an iOS project (a music platform) using the Swift language. Yangon, I developed five Android projects for company customer projects, both with single Myanmar (Burma) and group members. • I developed music streaming, shopping, and accounting system apps. Internship, New Westminster Institute 05/2017 - 09/2017

Education

Bachelor of Computer Science, *University of Computer Studies Yangon* □

Developed and maintained a single project.

2012 – 2017

Yangon,

- Completed all required coursework in computer science, including data structures, algorithms, software engineering, and computer systems.
- Yangon, Myanmar (Burma)

Myanmar (Burma)

• Developed strong programming skills in languages such as Java, PHP, and C++.

• I learned about web technology, mobile technology, and company architecture.

• Completed a capstone project where I developed a web-based application for managing inventory and sales for small businesses.

Projects

TrueID ☑

• Main focus on TrueID international products.

ShippingContainerHotel 🛮

• Developed while working in Gtriip company.

CDG Zig ♂

• Earlier know as comfortDelgro taxi app. Developed while working in Codigo.

Eleven News 🖸

• As a freelance project.

Oway Ride 🛮

- As a freelance project.
- Support Huawei Mobile Service in Oway Ride app
- Integrated HMS Push Kit, Map Kit and Location Kit in multiple modules

MM - Online Institute (MMOI) 🗗

• As a freelance project.

Communities contribution

 Devfest Yangon 2022, GDG Yangon Sharing about "Code review process and how we applied in team" speakerdeck link ☑ 	2022
 Public speak at Android 11 Meetups, GDG Yangon Sharing "Android 11 Privacy" speakerdeck link ☑ 	2020
 Sealed Classes and State Management Team sharing at Codigo company speakerdeck link ☑ 	2020
 Firebase Remote Config Team sharing in Codigo company speakerdeck link ☑ 	2020
 Public speak at Droid Yangon 2019, Droid Yangon Sharing "Do and Don't on Android Development" speakerdeck link ☑ 	2019